# **RUTH K. RHUADA**

#### **JUNIOR DATA ANALYST**

+234 810 046 1073

ruthny16@gmail.com
https://www.linkedin.com/in/ruth-kingsley-61147a136/
https://ruthkingsley.github.io

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I am a versatile, analytical and technological savvy with a strong passion of practically getting things done and dedicated to achieving best results. I have an excellent understanding and proficiency of platforms for effective data analyses including SQL, Spreadsheets, Tableau, Power BI and R. Demonstrated expertise in collaborating with highly proactive teams to ensure proper data collection, transformation, modelling, analyzing data and generating insights to help make informed decisions.

## **CORE COMPETENCIES**

- Strong analytical skills
- Data Modelling and Analysis
- Data Cleaning
- Strong data visualization skills
- Proficiency with Spreadsheets, SQL, Tableau and Power BI
- Effective presentation skills
- Communication skills
- Collaboration

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# **Data Analytics Intern**

Side Hustle Nigeria, Lagos. October 2021 – December 2021

- Improved knowledge on advance MS Excel formulas and tools.
- Executed all individual tasks to completion and on time.
- Collaborated with team members to get a 100% completion of tasks.
- Transformed, Analyzed and Visualized Data with Power Query and MS Power
- Data collection and Extraction using technological tools.
- Developed reports and created dashboards to help generate insights.

#### IT / Travel Associate

Travel Lab Nigeria Limited, Uyo. February 2020 – March 2021

- Provide IT and technical support to the organization.
- Manage and maintain company website and official records.
- Optimize online presence to increase customer base.
- Manage Client relationship and satisfaction.
- Book flights tickets for clients.
- Collate weekly and monthly Internet marketing report .

# **Performance Manager**

Paycom Nigeria Limited, Uyo. September 2019 – November 2019

- Optimize rider's performance and activities online.
- Managing Client relationship and satisfaction
- Provided training to clients in the use of company's product.
- Liaised with issues resolution department when required to escalate and resolve issues and/or report faults.
- Collate daily report for performance.

## **Digital Skills Training Tutor (Volunteer)**

Caywood Brown Foundation, Port Harcourt. September 2018

- Train participants on Google Digital Skills.
- Teach and delivered lectures on basics of web development
- Taught how to create a site with the building blocks of HTML5 and CSS3.
- Evaluate performance of participants on the different topics.

## **Web Developer Intern**

The Roothub Accelerator Systems October 2017 – July 2018

- Designed and Developed responsive websites for clients.
- Executes full-stack website launches specializing in front-end features, browser manipulation and cross browser compatibility.
- Developed and Deployed a semi-health website using technologies like JavaScript, NPM, Node.js, Express and Git.
- Researched industry trends to provide top quality design.
- Presented website mock-ups to clients to give them visual understanding of the end product and to ensure quality delivery of all parameters.

## **EDUCATION**

- Postgraduate Diploma in Business Administration
   National Open University of Nigeria, Abuja (In view)
- Bachelor of Agriculture (Crop Science)
   University of Uyo, Uyo 2017

## **CERTIFICATION**

- Google Data Analytics Certificate Coursera 2022
- Data Analytics
   Side Hustle Internship 2021
- Jobberman Soft-Skills Training
   Jobberman Nigeria 2020
- Excel Skills for Business Coursera 2020
- Introduction to Data Analysis Using Excel Coursera 2020
- Front-End Web UI Frameworks and Tools: Bootstrap 4
   The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology 2019
- Customer Relationship Management
   HP LIFE e-learning 2019
- The Fundamentals of Digital Marketing Google Digital Skills – 2018